Guide to the Moreno Family Houston Experience Collection
University of Houston Libraries
Moreno Family Houston Experience Collection
1972-2006
1972-1976
2010-012
Moreno family
1.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection contains meeting minutes, treasury reports, correspondence, and documents related to the meetings of the Political Association of Spanish Speaking Organizations (PASSO).
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Conferencia de Mujeres por la Raza; Political Association of Spanish-Speaking Organizations
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Minutes (administrative records)
Acquisition Information:
Donated by Susan E. Moreno, October 8, 2010
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Related Materials:
Emilio R. Ypiñia Journals digital collection (http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/2010_013)
Scope and Contents
This collection contains meeting minutes, treasury reports, correspondence, and documents related to the meetings of the Political Association of Spanish Speaking Organizations (PASSO).
This collection also contains documents about the organization of the Conferencia de Mujeres por la Raza. Lastly, this collection contains some typewritten copies of biographies of famous individuals. Materials are arranged chronologically.
Detailed List of Contents
- Political Association of Spanish Speaking Organizations (PASSO)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains meeting minutes, treasury reports, and other operational documents of PASSO.
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, January 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, February 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, March 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, April 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, May 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, June 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, July 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, August 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, September-December 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, January-February 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - PASSO Meeting Minutes & Related Documents, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, January 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, February 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, March 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, May 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, June 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, August 1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, October 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, November 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Governing Documents (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Member rosters (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - ¿Que Pasó? Newsletters (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Sons of Zapata (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Rules of the Democratic Party of Texas” (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - New Constitution for Texas (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - PASSO letterhead (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973-2006 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973-2006 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Conferencia de Mujeres por La Raza
  This series contains organizing documents from the National Chicana Conference.
  - Conferencia de Mujeres por La Raza (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Personal
  This series contains typewritten copies of the book Masters of Achievement in English, and a document entitled “Datos Biograficos” in Spanish, which includes biographical data on various historical figures.
  - Roman History (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Datos Biograficos" (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Masters of Achievement” (Box 1, Folder 33)